Ingrid Burrington 想要走进云的世界
Ingrid Burrington wanted to walk inside a cloud.
不是真实的“一朵云”哟
Not just “a cloud.” though.
而是“云计算”的世界
The cloud.
我不知道互联网真正的样子
I don't know what the internet looks like,
我也不认为互联网是我想象中的那样
I don't think it looks like this.
所以我想尝试找出它真实的模样
I wanted to just kind of find out.
Ingrid 是一名记者
Ingrid's a journalist.
在她为《大西洋》撰写的系列报道中
For a series she wrote for the Atlantic,
她讲述了自己参观一个数据中心的经历
she talked her way into one of the datacenters,
那是个我们网络生活越来越依赖的地方
where more and more of our online lives play out.
在那里 她发现的东西与“云”这个词相差甚远：
What she found there wasn't all fluffy and white,
是实实在在的、摸得着的事物
it was downright physical.
首先 她要拍照登记 申请访客身份卡
First up, getting her photo taken for an ID tag.
然后 要通过安检站
Next, going through security checkpoints
签署一份保密协议
and signing a nondisclosure agreement.
最后 她才能去看机房
Finally, she gets to see the machines.
机房基本上就像个仓库 就像超市的那样 但比它大得多
The server rooms are basically warehouses, think Costco, but bigger.
整个机房看起来有种别样的美
And there's something beautiful about that warehouse look,
所有的东西都整齐陈列着
because everything's just there on display.
一排排毫无遮拦的服务器上
Racks of naked servers,
连接着通往世界各地的线缆
and above them all the cables connecting to the world,
它们沿着天花板上的轨道整齐布线
running along tracks on the ceiling.
眩目的蓝色指示灯闪烁着
There's a sort of fancy blue light going on,
让人想到《电子世界争霸战》里的场景
kind of a Tron thing.
*《电子世界争霸战》（Tron），一系列科幻电影，第一部上映于 1982 年，国内亦将本系列名称译为“创”
这个系列以使用荧光色衬以灰暗背景来营造科技感的美术风格而闻名 - 视频制作者注
但占据了大部分空间的 还是贪婪渴求着电力的一行行服务器
But mostly, it's rows and rows of very hungry servers.
*《电子世界争霸战》（Tron），一系列科幻电影，第一部上映于 1982 年，国内亦将本系列名称译为“创”
这个系列以使用荧光色衬以灰暗背景来营造科技感的美术风格而闻名 - 视频制作者注
但占据了大部分空间的 还是贪婪渴求着电力的一行行服务器
But mostly, it's rows and rows of very hungry servers.
全球范围内的所有数据中心每年消耗的能源比整个英国还要多
Datacenters use up more energy each year than the whole of the United Kingdom.
这就意味着它们会释放惊人的巨大热量
And that means they're throwing off crazy amounts of heat,
这就是为什么当 Ingrid 环顾四周时…
which is why when Ingrid looks around ...
我发现这座建筑主要的设计理念
This is a building that's mostly designed around
是建造最理想最完美的暖通系统
having the most perfect HVAC system imaginable.
Ingrid 发现 围绕数据中心的一切都强调经济实用
Ingrid discovered that everything about a datacenter is pragmatic,
简单说就是一堆主机
so yeah just a bunch of machines,
一堆线缆、一堆风扇
a bunch of cables, a bunch of fans,
放在一大块租金便宜的地皮上 用大量廉价的工业用水来冷却
on lots of cheap land, using lots of cheap water to keep it cool.
完全没有“云”这个词本身散发的浪漫
Not quite what the word "cloud" represents,
但另一方面 我们的生活、我们的工作以及我们的话语
but on the other hand, it's our lives, our work, our voices
都在这个服务器的仓库里回响着
bouncing around in that warehouse of machines.
是的 这有点超现实
Yeah, it can be a little surreal
并不是说我就知道那台机器里存有某人的电子邮件
because it's not as though it's like I know that machine has someone's email,
这台机器又存有别的东西
and that machine has something else.
而是我意识到…
But realizing kind of just how...
周围有很多看不见的事情正在发生
how much is kind of happening around me implicitly that I can't see,
我能从声音里听得出来
but I can kind of hear
不管是服务器的呼呼声也好
in the sense of the whirring of the machines
还是其它的各种声音也好
and the larger kind of operation of the space.
机房让我觉得庄严而怪异
There is something a little bit eerie about it,
就像是面对工业的力量 人会肃然起敬
and I mean there's sort of like an industrial awe ...
时刻要记住 在我们使用服务的时候 它们的基础
It's so important to remember that these buildings really are there,
也就是这些建筑 总在某个隐蔽的角落嗡嗡运作着
somewhere, humming behind the fence.
这之所以重要 是因为
Because here's the thing,
当我们谈论在云上存储东西 或创建应用程序时
when we talk about storing stuff on the cloud, or building an app on the cloud,
我们有时会自欺欺人地认为它就像天上的云
we sometimes fool ourselves into thinking it's like a cloud in the sky,
是没有人能触碰的存在
something nobody can touch.
但现实恰恰相反
But the reality is exactly the opposite,
一旦我们认识到云数据中心真实存在于某地
and once we remember where the cloud lives,
我们就会开始思考谁拥有着云了
we can start talking about who owns the cloud.
那么是谁在控制这些服务器、线缆和风扇呢？
Who controls all those servers, and cables, and fans?
它们又是如何改变开发者的工作方式的呢？
And how does that change the way developers build the future?
云让我们紧密地连接在一起
Because in cloud city, we're all living there together.
我是 Saron Yitbarek 这里是《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek, and this is Command Line Heroes.
一档由红帽公司推出的原创播客节目
An original podcast from Red Hat,
第六集 揭秘云计算
episode six, Crack the Cloud Open.
没有所谓的“云” 那只是别人的电脑
There is no cloud, it's just someone else's computer.
Chris Watterston 是一名设计师 他对围绕云产生的误解很是恼火
Chris Watterston is a designer who grew annoyed at the confusion around the cloud.
这个词模糊了数据中心的形象
That word had softened the edges of datacenters,
就像 Ingrid 参观过的那个一样
like the one Ingrid visited.
当 Chris 把这句口号做成贴纸时
When he put that slogan on a sticker,
他因此成为了网红
he became internet famous.
“没有所谓的‘云’ 那只是别人的电脑”
That line "There is no cloud, it's just someone else's computer,"
这句话现在出现在 T 恤、帽衫、咖啡杯、海报、
is now on t-shirts, hoodies, coffee mugs, posters,
杯垫和许多主题演讲上
coasters, and more than a few keynote presentations.
人们完全不理解云是什么 还用的很欢乐又心安
People sort of still use the cloud as if it's going up there,
他们可能完全误解了云
people that don't understand fully what it is, they can still take it sort of the wrong way
不明白他们的数据实际上是穿过铜轴电缆、或者光纤
and not understand that their data is actually going across copper cables, or fibers,
来到某一个实际上由他人管理和拥有的存储设备
whatever it might be into a storage device that is actually managed and owned by someone else.
显然 对于一些有需要隐藏的私人内容的人来说
Which obviously, for some people, if they've got private content they want to hide,
这是相当可怕的隐患
could be quite scary.
所以 下次你想把东西扔到云上的时候 想想 Chris 的贴纸吧
So think of Chris's sticker next time you're tossing something onto the cloud.
想想你到底要扔到哪里去
Where are you really tossing it?
在 App 上工作也是同样道理
Same goes for working on an app,
所谓“无服务器”的说法都是骗人的 根本没有这回事
for all the talk of going serverless, there's really no such thing.
云就是别人的服务器、别人的电脑
It's somebody else's server, somebody else's computer.
不过云这件事情从某种意义上说 是一种成长
In a sense, this is a story about growing up.
整一季节目里 我们一直在追溯开源的成长与变革
All season long, we've been tracking the evolution of open source.
从最初的自由软件运动到 Linux 的诞生
From its rebellious origins with the free software movement, and the emergence of Linux,
直至今天 开源工具和方法把我们带到了远离家园的云端
all the way to today when open source tools and methods have taken us far from home into the cloud.
可以打个比方 一个人找房东租房
Think of it this way, when a person finds an apartment to rent,
她需要签合同、搬进去、把房子整理成自己的居所
she's going to sign a contract, move in, and make it her own.
当开发者寻找云供应商时 他们也在做着同样的事情
When developers go looking for a cloud provider, they have to do the same thing.
这就是我们现在所处的情况
That's the moment we're in right now,
全世界的开发者都在转向各种云上线产品
the moment when a whole world of developers is making their move onto a series of clouds,
然后开始明白租赁的真实含义
and starting to figure out what the rental lease actually says.
严肃地发问一句 为什么我们一开始就急着跳上云端呢
Just for the record, why are we in such a rush to hop onto a cloud in the first place?
因为开发者不想维护 App 运行所需的设备
Developers don't want to have to manage the infrastructure that is running their applications.
这位是 Brandon Butler 《网络世界》的高级编辑
This is Brandon Butler, he's the senior editor at Network World.
多年来致力于研究云计算
And he's been covering cloud computing for years.
开发者想要开发 App 部署 App
They want to develop apps, and they want to deploy those apps,
并只在乎 App 能不能正常运行
and they want those apps to just run.
我们已经看到云孕育的 越来越多的服务 例如无服务器计算
And more and more, we've seen things like serverless computing,
功能即服务
and functions-as-a-service,
以及容器和容器管理平台 如 Kubernetes
and containers, and container management platforms, like Kubernetes.
顺便打个广告
Check out episode five, by the way,
想了解容器和 Kubernetes 请看我们的上期节目
for a run-down on containers and Kubernetes.
这些技术将 App 运行所依赖的底层细节隐藏了起来
All these things are helping to abstract away the underlying infrastructure that applications need to run on.
这将是一个可以在未来可预见的持续发展的趋势
And that's going to be a trend that we're only going to see continue to develop into the future.
云拥有巨大吸引力的部分原因 可以用“超大规模”这个词来解释
A big part of that attraction is summed up by the word hyperscale.
通过云为你提供的所有基础设施
With the cloud providing all your infrastructure,
初创公司可以迅速扩张或者收缩自己的服务
you can take a startup and scale it up, or down, as fast as you want.
你不再需要购买自己的设备 你只需要租赁你想要的规模的云
You're not building your own infrastructure anymore, you're just renting out however much of the cloud you need.
Brandon 解释了“超大规模”对初创公司的具体帮助
Brandon explains what hyperscale means for a startup.
使用公有云进行 App 开发的整套模型
This whole model of using the public cloud for application development
对开发者来说是一个巨大的进步
has been a huge advance for application developers.
它曾经成就了一系列全新的初创公司
It's created a whole new range of startups,
这些初创公司也已经成长为大众都喜欢投资的公司
and companies that have grown past startups and become major publicly funded companies.
想想 Netflix 这样的公司
You think about a company like Netflix
它的大部分后端都运行在亚马逊的以及其他的云上
that runs much of its backend infrastructure on Amazon's cloud, and other cloud providers as well.
这些公司现在如此壮大的原因 正是他们在使用云
They were able to turn into what they are, because they are using the cloud.
因此 云对开发者的影响是不可轻视的
So the impact that the cloud has had on developers cannot be understated.
云已经成为过去十年 App 开发领域的主要转变
It's been the major shift in application development over the last decade.
Nick Bush 是 Meadowbrook 保险公司的一位系统管理员
Nick Bush, a sys admin at Meadowbrook Insurance
他还记得在云计算诞生之前 调整基础设施是多么痛苦的事
remembers what a pain infrastructure changes were before the cloud.
以前 有些人想出新项目的点子
Before, it was somebody would come up with an idea to do a certain project,
我们会说 “这需要硬件支持 而我们没有”
and we would say, "That would need hardware to do that."
他们会问 “那么我们该怎么办？”
And they would ask, "Well, how do we do that?"
我们以前总是受到内存的限制
So we were always constrained by memory,
尤其是运行虚拟机软件 通常是最困难的部分
and VM-ware usually was the hard part.
我们经常需要在任意时间启动虚拟机
And we would be constrained by how many virtual machines we could spin up at any one given time.
但能随时启动的虚拟机数量总是不多
所以我们不得不花很多钱买新处理器
So we would have to go get a quote for new processors,
新内存、新硬件 或者花 5000 美元加新的东西
new memory, new hardware, $5,000 added space, and stuff like that.
一旦我们从几个不同的供应商得到报价
And once we get those quotes from a couple of different vendors,
就得报给管理层 他们要花时间审核
it would go to management, and they would take time.
这样 仅仅是购买硬件都需要漫长的过程
It was a long, drawn-out process just to get the hardware in.
更不要说构建虚拟机 再反复考虑和测试等等
Let alone, then build the VMs and turn them over and test and stuff like that.
所以其实我的意思是
So I mean
有了云 我们可以在几个小时内
there were several months of front-end work
完成以往需要几个月完成的前期工作
versus now we can definitely get that okay within a couple hours usually.
让虚拟机运行起来 第二天就交付给其他人
And go spin it up, and go turn it over to them the next day.
在周转时间上 这是个很大的改变
So it is a big turnaround difference.
在拓展性、速度和价格这些方面
Between scalability, speed, and price,
云计算相当吸引人
the cloud can look very tempting.
还是拿租房作比喻
To go back to the apartment rental analogy,
云就像可以让你免费得到一个管家和司机的服务
cloud options can feel like you're getting a butler and a driver at no additional cost.
你很难对云计算说不
It's hard to say no,
如今市场上有主要的四家壮志雄心的云供应商在开疆拓土
and today we've got four very ambitious cloud providers doing the tempting.
他们都想成为你在云上的“新房东”
They all want to be your new landlord in cloud city.
但是且慢 每个租过房子的人都知道
But hold up, everyone who's rented a home
租房和买房不一样
knows it's not the same as buying.
你不能自己拆掉一堵墙 或者安装一个新的按摩浴缸
You can't just knock down a wall, or install a new jacuzzi.
你得通过房东来干这些事
You got to go through the landlord.
我们使用公有云 在某种程度上会受制于一家独资公司
In some ways, could we be stuck if we find ourselves beholden to a single proprietary company?
这会不会对我们不利？
Brandon Butler 先生
Brandon Butler.
当你使用云供应商提供的公有云时
When you use a proprietary cloud vendor,
你有不同的使用方法
there are different ways you can use it.
你可以拥抱开源标准和开源平台
You can use it in a way that embraces open source standards and open source platforms
并且在云上运行开源软件
and run those open source platforms
即使这云本身是供应商的专有服务
on top of a cloud that even may be proprietary,
你也可以使用不是开源的原生工具
or you can use native tools to those cloud providers that may not be as open source,
这些工具可能在公有云上有更好的集成
but they may have stronger integrations to the public cloud platform.
因此 这是终端用户必须考虑的一个重大问题
So, it's a big trade-off that end users have to consider.
我是想使用云供应商的原生工具
Do I want to use tools that are native to the cloud provider
这些工具可能与这个云供应商提供的服务
that may be more heavily integrated with the services
以及其他服务更好的集成
this cloud provider offers and other services that I might want to use also on that cloud,
还是拥抱开源标准 使用一个开源平台
or do I want to prioritize using an open source platform
享受更高的自由度
that will give me more freedom
在自己和其他提供商的平台上也能运行？
to run that maybe on my own infrastructure or another cloud provider's infrastructure?
随着我们所依赖的云技术不断发展
As the clouds we rely on keep growing
四大云供应商相互竞争
and the big four cloud providers elbow past each other for dominance,
我们作为开发者有了新选择
we developers have a choice.
我们是放弃一些独立性
Do we give up some of our independence,
依靠单一的云供应商来保护我们的工作
relying on a single cloud provider to protect our work,
还是选择另一条路
or could we take another road,
在保持独立性的同时最大化云的拓展性?
maximize the scalability of the cloud while keeping our independence?
换句话说 我们能否在租房合同上写明
In other words, can we sign a lease that says,
“房客有权任意处置该房 例如拆墙或其他装修”？
"Sure. Do what you want with the place. Knock a wall down. Make it your own?"
那么 放弃一点点独立性又有什么问题呢？
So, what's the problem with giving up a little independence?
如果你是一名开发者 可能没受到什么影响
If you're a developer, it might not be so obvious.
因为大多数时候都有运维团队
That's because it's mostly been the ops teams
在背后监督开发者们小心行事
who've been encouraging us to tread lightly.
他们格外留心于具体细节
They noticed the nuts-and-bolts issues.
这位是 Major Hayden 他是 Rackspace 的首席架构师
Here's Major Hayden. He's the principal architect at Rackspace.
有些时候 开发者经常发现他们有各种不同的需要
Developers will often find that over time they may have requirements for different things
比如某些专门化的存储
like a certain specialized kind of storage,
或者可能想要一定大小的虚拟机
or they may want to have a certain sized VM,
或者想要一种云供应商未能提供的东西
or maybe they want a type of offering that the cloud provider doesn't offer,
还有一些东西可能开发者没有第一时间想要
and there's also some of those things that you do have to look at
但你认为他们需要的
that developers aren't always the first ones to look at,
对这些东西你还要进行成本效益分析
where you have to do that cost benefit analysis to understand,
好吧 虽然使用公有云我们有很大的灵活性
okay, I have a lot of flexibility in public cloud,
但我们到底付出了什么代价？
but how much does that really cost me?
Major 指出了另一个问题 这个问题超越了实用性
Major points out another issue, one that goes beyond practicalities
并且触及了像我这样的开发人员所信奉的核心
and speaks to the heart of what developers like me believe in.
那就是开源实践
I'm talking about open source practices.
即使云供应商允许你使用自己的开源工具
Even if cloud providers allow you to use your open source tools,
但云本身并不是开源的
they're not themselves open.
因此 开源对于云来说是一个需要处理的有趣议题
So, open source in the cloud is an interesting subject to tackle
因为有大量的开源技术支持用户去高效地利用公有云
because there's plenty of open source technologies that allow you to take advantage of a public cloud,
但并不是所有公有云都把它们的基础设施开源了
but not all public clouds have their infrastructure offered as open source.
举个例子 如果你使用亚马逊
So for example, if you take Amazon,
你无法知道他们使用的什么技术来构建虚拟机和其他服务
you're not able to actually see what they're using to build VMs or build other services,
所以 你不可能对这些东西做点调整
so if you wanted to make an adjustment for that, you really wouldn't be able to,
或者很难了解幕后的机理和运作方法
or if you wanted to look behind the scenes and understand
more of how it fits together, that would be difficult.
如果你听过我们之前关于 DevOps 的节目
If you listened to our episode on DevOps,
你会知道打破开发者和运维之间的壁垒会让我们获益良多
you know there's a lot we can gain by tearing down the wall between developers and operations.
架构师 Major 刚给了我们一些真知灼见
Architects like Major give us some crucial insights,
接下来的这位是系统管理员 Nick Bush
and then there's sys admin, Nick Bush.
他所在的团队正准备向云端迁移
He's on a team where people are ready to jump on the cloud.
开发者们已经厌倦了每五年一次硬件换代
Developers are tired of being stuck with physical hardware that ages every five years,
每个人都喜欢尽可能快地扩展
and everyone likes the idea of expanding as fast as they want,
而 Nick 想指出一些开发者可能没有考虑到的东西
but Nick wants to flag things that developers might not be considering.
是的 我想说的是 云是存在延迟的
Yeah. I mean, there is inherent latency.
举个例子 就像远在蒙大拿的数据库服务器
I mean, that is a database server in Montana
比起我用 10Gbps 带宽直连街对面的机房
versus my 10-gig connection down the street,
单是数据库调用就会花费更长的时间
so just doing local database calls is gonna take longer.
因为你和服务器之间相距更远了
It is a longer path to get there,
也有各种安全上的因素
and there's other security stuff that's out there
如果在自己的机房里 至少物理层面上不必担心
that we didn't have to worry about physical premise.
毕竟我们能管控自己使用的硬件
Here, we were in control of our hardware and stuff like that.
一旦换成云 你就得考虑可能进出服务器的其它连接
Once you are in the cloud, you gotta think about the other connections coming into that.
因此我认为云的安全性还是较低一些
You gotta worry about security, I think, a little bit more,
这也涉及到成本因素
and it is a price thing.
你想要按月租一个云端虚拟机 要求网速快
Every month you want a sped-up VM,
而且带有充足的存储空间
take up storage space.
每千兆的传输和存储都是要花钱的
It is a cost per gigabyte, (you know,) transferred as well as stored,
以前我们直接买服务器 买来之后它就任我们处置了
where before we had a one-time purchase and we just had it there,
我们可以把它存放起来 也可以拿出来使用
and we could store it, use it.
只要还有地方放它 就不必花更多钱
We didn't have to pay anymore money as long as we had space for it.
声明一下 Nick 确实认为此事利大于弊
For the record, Nick does think the pluses outweigh the minuses.
他只是不想让我们认为这是个完美的系统
He just doesn't want us to pretend it's a perfect system.
如果你的云供应商宕机
What happens if your provider has an outage
而你想在其他云中重新部署应用程序 会发生什么情况？
and you want to re-deploy an application in another cloud?
或者 如果在不同事务上使用不同的云能带来价格优势呢？
Or what if there's a price advantage to using different clouds for different things?
运维人员提出的这些问题都可以被总结于一个词汇下
A lot of the issues that the ops folks bring up can fit under a single label,
也就是供应商依赖
vendor lock-in.
你可能很熟悉这个词
You're probably familiar with this term.
供应商依赖的意思是 在别人的服务器上构建业务
It's the concept that building on someone else's server
会让你越来越依赖于他们的平台
gets you more and more tied to their platform.
你被绑定在这个平台了
You get locked in.
可能突然之间 你被迫升级系统、付出更多成本、接受新限制
Suddenly, you're being force fed upgrades, cost changes, new limits
你变得身不由己 你懂的
you wouldn't have chosen for yourself. You get the idea.
如果我们采取 DevOps 的工作方式
When we put our DevOps hats on,
开发者和运维就可以一起工作
we can work together to see lock-in coming
面对供应商锁定 对症下药
and plan around it,
如果开发者和运维都只是各自为战
but when we're buried in our own code,
我们有时就会忘记观览全局
we sometimes forget to look at the whole picture.
为什么不找个折中方法 同时在公共和私有云上工作呢？
What about finding the right mix, working on both public and private clouds?
终极解决方案可能是混合云
The ultimate solution might be in a hybrid cloud,
兼具公有和私有云的优点
the best of both worlds.
我给 Bridget Kromhout 打了电话 询问她的看法
I called up Bridget Kromhout to get her perspective.
她是微软员工中的头号云开发提倡者
She's a principal cloud developer advocate over at Microsoft,
对这方面非常了解
and knows this stuff backwards and forwards.
如果我们考虑一种混合的解决方案
So, if we think about the hybrid solution
既包含一些公有云 也包含一些私有云
having a little bit of that public cloud, but then also some of that private cloud,
这是两者之间的完美平衡吗？
is that the perfect balance between the two?
对于开发者 这是理想的解决方案吗？
Is that the ideal solution for developers?
如果云是混合的 那么我就能想做什么就做什么
If it's hybrid, then I can kind of do whatever I want and
想用什么工具就用什么
use whatever tools that I want on my end,
同时仍然可以从大型公有云提供商那里获得一些好处
but then still get some of the benefits of the big public cloud providers.
当然是的
Absolutely.
举个例子 我有朋友在制造业中从事高性能计算研究工作
So, for example, I have friends who work in high-performance computing research at manufacturing companies,
他们有各种各样的绝密资料
and they have all sorts of top secret,
或者有保密协议的资料 这样的东西不适合放在公有云上
NDA, whatever stuff that they don't feel comfortable putting on public cloud,
于是 他们可能会在自己的数据中心跟这些资料打交道
and so maybe they're going to work in their datacenters on these workloads,
处理客户数据 或者研究数据
crunching these customer numbers or whatever, these research numbers,
他们可能也有…
and then they may have other...
他们确实也有适合放在公有云上的其他工作资料
They do have other workloads that they feel comfortable having out in public cloud,
不过我想这个问题就…
but I think this is kind of a question of...
有时也会有这样的问题 公有云是否适合某些工作资料
And sometimes there's questions, too, of whether public cloud has suitability for some of the workloads,
比如 如果你本来计划要用 InfiniBand 连接各个不同节点
like if you're planning on using InfiniBand interconnects between your nodes,
[中文维基百科] InfiniBand 是一个用于高性能计算的计算机网络通信标准，它具有极高的吞吐量和极低的延迟
也用作服务器与存储系统之间的直接或交换互连，以及存储系统之间的互连 - 视频制作者注
公有云又能满足这种需求到什么程度呢
how much of that are you gonna be able to provision in public cloud?
但这并不一定是完美的解决方案
But this isn't necessarily the perfect solution.
Bridget 认为混合云也有自身的弊端
Bridget does think that hybrid clouds come with their own headaches.
混合云的问题在于
The problem with hybrid is
有时 人们欺骗自己
sometimes people fool themselves
以为自己可以接受一些实际上不成熟的方案
and think that they can take something that really wasn't working,
如果他们使用私有的服务器 部署一个虚拟机可能需要两周
so if they had their old processes with a two-week wait time to even get a single VM,
然后出现了某种特殊情况 导致没办法等这么久
if they have a whole scenario like that and it wasn't working well,
就会有一群人拿出信用卡
and then they have a bunch of people who have started taking their credit cards
找到公有云提供商准备租服务器了 因为他们失望极了
to the public cloud providers because they're frustrated,
然后他们又想办法把公有云和原先的系统粘合在一起
and then they try to somehow glue those together,
这样一来就会出现数据来源和延迟的问题
but then there's problems with data provenance and latency
或者…我不知道 像是数据集脱同步之类的问题
and, I don't know, de-synced data sets,
出错的方式可以有很多种
there's a lot of ways it can go wrong.
我认为 如果你和云服务提供商合作
I think if you work with your cloud providers
或许会有成熟可靠的直连方案*
you can add some of the direct connection things that are available
*而不是在这里手搓混合云 - 视频制作者注
这样你就可以更好地同步数据
so that you can sync things better,
这样是很有帮助的
that can help.
是的 当我们在开源的语境下谈到云的时候
Yeah. So, when we talk about the cloud in the context of open source,
我觉得 作为开发者
I feel like as developers we,
可能大多数人 都喜欢开源；
I think most of us, really like open source,
如果你还在听我们的播客节目 就更是这样 对吧？
especially if you're listening to this podcast. Right?
你希望一切都是开放的 透明的 还向大众共享代码
You want everything to be open and transparent and share the code and all that,
但我觉得 当我们谈到云计算
but I feel like when we talk about the cloud,
因为它不会给人感觉是代码库
because it doesn't feel like its own code base,
不会让人觉得云本身是个项目
doesn't feel like its own project,
它是环境 是可以用来帮助我们运行代码的东西
it's the environment, it's the thing that we can use to help us run our code,
开发人员们还会坚持要让它
are developers as insistent on that part of the story
像是传统的项目和代码库一样开源、透明吗？
being open source and transparent the way that we
sometimes feel very strongly about when it comes to our projects and our code base?
我觉得这是一个非常合理的问题
I think that's a really reasonable question,
我觉得这可能也会归结到你到底要注目于技术栈的哪一部分
and I think that might also come down to exactly where in the stack are you going to pick to care about,
想一想 你对芯片的了解有多少？你又能在何种程度上操控它们？
because if you think about it, how much access to and info do you have about the chips?
确实 你说得有道理
Yeah, that's true. That's fair.
他们坐在那里 他们有硅 他们也有秘密
Sitting over there with some silicon and some secrets.
他们不一定会将后者给你
They're not necessarily giving that to you.
[Saron] Silicon and secrets. That's a good podcast name, by the way.
[Saron] 顺便 “硅和秘密”很适合做播客的名字
对吧？也许问题不在于是否一切都是开放的
Right? Maybe the question is not is everything open,
而在于你需要开放的一切是否都是开放的
but is everything open that you need to be open,
以及 当服务没有完全按照正确的方式运行时
and of course, is your provider gonna have transparency with you
你的服务提供者是否会对你保持信息透明
when things don't operate exactly as they should,
如果没有的话 事情不好解决
because hopefully they will.
我能理解 Bridget 作为公有云提供商的立场
So, I get Bridget's perspective as a public cloud provider,
她提出了一个有趣的观点
and she makes an interesting point.
开发者对云的控制究竟需要深入到什么程度呢？
How granular does a developer's control need to be on the cloud?
至于我 我的看法不一样
As for me, I look at it differently.
我不想为了一点公有云的优势而牺牲的是什么呢？
What don't I want to sacrifice in order to get some of that public cloud goodness?
比如说 一个应用在公有云上运行
Say an app is running on a public cloud
然后 等一下 现在我已经扩大了规模
and then, wait a minute, now I've scaled up
或者有新的合规要求
or there's new compliance requirements
我的应用在私有云上更合适
and it makes more sense for my app to be in a private cloud.
把应用从一个地方迁移到另一个地方之前
Moving that app point to point,
我需要知道它在迁移之后仍能工作
I need to know it's going to work.
我需要知道它是以原先同样的方式打包 以同样的方式配置
I need to know things are packaged the same way, configured the same way.
换句话说
In other words,
我需要知道从一个云跳到另一个云总是可能的
I need to know that jumping from cloud to cloud is always possible.
除此之外 我们还有什么选择？
What's the alternative?
仅仅锁定在一家云提供商？
Getting locked into just one cloud provider?
一个甚至可能完全垄断整个行业的供应商？
A provider that might even gain a total monopoly over all the others?
不能选择迁移到另一个环境的话
Not having the option to move to a different environment,
这就像把一只手绑在背后写代码一样
that's like trying to code with one hand tied behind your back.
所以 我们不想欠下任何一朵云的人情 并且被它困住
So, we don't want to be trapped and beholden to any one cloud.
我们希望在合适的时候能够在云间跳转
We want to be able to cloud hop when it suits us.
用摇滚传奇皇后乐队的名言来说
In the immortal words of rock legend Queen,
“我想要挣脱束缚”
“I want to break free.”
我们希望能够获得公有云的绝佳拓展性
We want access to that fantastic scalability you find in public clouds,
但又不放弃使用开源工具和方法所带来的自由
but without giving up the freedoms that we've come to expect from using open-sourced tools and methods.
有个好消息 混合云的建设正在顺利进行中
Here's the good news. The work on those hybrid clouds is well underway.
Mike Ferris 红帽公司的的业务架构副总裁
Mike Ferris, VP of Business Architecture at Red Hat
他给出了一个很好的解释
gives a great explanation
说明了混合云是如何帮助我们保持开源精神的
of how hybrid clouds help us maintain that open source ethos.
开源是世界上几乎每一个云服务的基础
Open source is really the base for almost every cloud in the world
就算不能说“所有的基础设施和工具”都来自于开源项目
and now many, if not most,
这个世界上也有许多应用程序的基础设施
of the application infrastructures in the world
以及相关的工具来自于开源
and the tooling evolves from that,
不管是用于管理项目的工具
the management capabilities,
还是用于构建和部署应用的工具
everything that people are using to build and deploy
不管这些应用是用于关键任务还是非关键任务
mission-critical applications as well as non-mission-critical applications
开发它们的工具全都基于开源
if it's all based on open source.
混合云的概念和这一点非常兼容
This concept of hybrid really flows alone with it
这代表着 我们可以在混合云中处处使用开源工具
meaning that they have the ability to use these things wherever they are
可以最大程度地发挥出基础设施的优势
to take advantage of the best feature sets on what infrastructure is there,
这是基于以下的一点事实：
all based upon this concept that
开源能在一定程度上规定将来的开发方式与技术标准
that open source is really helping define the standards that are driving this next generation of development
因为其当今的影响力相当强大
while they continue to leverage all the investments that they've made in the past.
我认为云计算本身具有开放的倾向
I think the cloud wants to be open.
在本季节目中 我们花了很多时间讨论开源的起源
We've spent a lot of time this season talking about the origins of open source.
你甚至可以证明
You can even make the case
某些版本的混合云是这些相同理想的延伸
that some version of hybrid would be an extension of those same ideals.
在过去几十年里 开源开发活动的变化是
What has changed in the open source development activities over the past several decades
越来越多的人参与进来了
has been that many more people have gotten involved,
包括像微软、IBM 这样的行业巨头
including people like Microsoft, IBM.
你知道 随便说个大公司的名字
You know, name a big corporation,
他们要么使用开源软件来提供产品
they're either using open source for their offerings
要么构建开源软件并将其回馈给社区
or they're building open source and contributing that back to the community
或者两项都参与
or some combination of both.
这些来自客户的重要需求通过大公司涌入
This influx of really important needs from customers through those large corporations
确实帮助了开源世界的发展
has really helped evolve open source
使之从最初设想中 Solaris 和 UNIX 环境的替代方案逐渐扩张
from being what was originally intended to displace the Solaris and UNIX environments,
如今 不仅是社区和业余爱好者使用开源工具
to something that's the basis for not just community and hobbyist use
部分企业也将自己的关键任务交托给开源
but also certainly mission-critical enterprise use.
开源正在快速成长
Open source is growing up, fast.
现在 我们有机会牢牢记住其初心
Now, we have the chance to make sure we remember where we come from.
当我们跃上云时 可以在其中保留属于自己的部分
As we hop on the cloud, we can claim part of it for ourselves
以此来保持云的开放
and keep the cloud open.
幸运的是 由于有了 OpenStack® 平台这样的工具
Luckily, building open source bridges between clouds is getting a lot easier
在云之间建造开源桥梁变得更加容易了
thanks to work like the OpenStack platform.
Rackspace 的首席架构师 Major Hayden 描述了它的起源
Major Hayden, principal architect at Rackspace, describes its origins.
OpenStack® 来自于 Rackspace 和 NASA 的合作：
It really came from Rackspace and NASA getting together and saying,
“你看 这是一种建设基础设施的新方式
"Hey look, this is a new way to build infrastructure
我们应该公开进行
and we should do it out in the open.
我们应该得到更多的意见 应该和更多的人交流
We should get more of this input. We should talk to more people.
我们得让更多人用它”
We should get more use cases."
OpenStack® 是一组应用
What OpenStack is, it's a group of applications
它能很好地协同创建基础设施
that work really well together to create infrastructure,
并全面管理基础设施
to manage infrastructure all across the board.
无论你需要复杂的虚拟机
Whether you need complex virtual machines,
复杂的网络
complex networking,
还是有奇怪的存储要求
you have strange storage requirements,
OpenStack® 通常可以满足大部分的要求
OpenStack can usually fit most of those.
Major 提到的这一点是开源项目独有的优势之一：
Major is talking about adding something that open source knows how to deliver.
极高的适应性
Adaptability.
在我看来
When I look at OpenStack,
OpenStack® 是一组相互连接的开源应用程序
I look at it as an interconnected set of open source applications
它让你能建设你想要的基础设施
that allow you to build the infrastructure that you want.
如果它不能满足你的需求
If it can't build what you want
你就可以进入社区 对它作出改变
then you can go in the community and make changes to it.
我喜欢我去和顾客交谈时他们的反应
I love the reaction when I go and talk to customers and they say,
“我们想修改这里 还有那里”
"Well we want to change this. We want to change this."
我们会说 “好呀 随便改吧”
We say, "Well, you can."
我们该如何确保未来的云也具有这种适应性呢？
How do we make sure that level of adaptability is enshrined in the cloud of tomorrow?
就像我们在之前的节目中谈到的许多问题一样
Like many issues we've talked about in past episodes,
这需要强大的社区
it's all about strong communities.
有请 Brandon Butler 《网络世界》的高级编辑
Brandon Butler, senior editor at Network World.
例如 我们已经看到了云原生计算基金会的成立
For example, we've seen the Cloud Native Computing Foundation be created
这个基金会制定标准
to create standards
他们推广应用容器的使用
and the use of application containers
并创造了 Kubernetes
and Kubernetes.
我们也看到了 OpenStack 基金会的成立
We've seen the OpenStack foundation be created
好将 OpenStack® 用户聚集在一起
to bring OpenStack users together
以此讨论创建开源基础设施服务云的最佳方式
to talk about best practices when creating open source infrastructure service clouds.
支撑这些开源社区的社群极为重要
The communities that underpin these open source communities
无论是开发将来的开源工具
are hugely important for developing the next wave of open source tools,
还是学习使用开源平台的最佳方式
for learning best practices about how to use these open source platforms,
甚至于鼓励公有云厂商接受开源标准这方面 他们都起到关键作用
and for encouraging these public cloud vendors to embrace these open source standards.
一旦我们开始建设混合云 并使其尽可能地开放
Once we start building that hybrid cloud, making it as open as possible,
其潜力似乎真的无穷无尽
the potential really seems endless.
有请 Major
Here's Major.
我最为乐见的就是
What I'm most excited about
越来越多的东西能横跨不同的云运行
is just to see more things that can come together on top of different clouds.
例如 OpenStack® 提供了一层很好的基础设施
For example, OpenStack provides a great base layer of infrastructure,
但你也能在其上作出很多改动
but then you can do so much on top of it.
我想有时候 有些公司会采用 OpenStack® 然后说
I think sometimes different companies will adopt OpenStack and then say,
“伙计 我现在该怎么办？
"Man, what do I do now?
我的自由程度太高了 我不知道该怎么办
I have all this freedom. I don't know what to do."
这就像你有一个装满食物的冰箱 你会想
It's kind of like when you have a refrigerator full of food and you're like,
“啊 我不知道该做什么菜”
"Ah, I don't know what to make."
这可真是种甜蜜的苦恼
I love having that problem.
Chris Watterson 告诉我们的可能是对的
Chris Watterson might have been right when he told us.
没有所谓的“云” 那只是别人的电脑
There is no Cloud. It's just someone else's' computer.
但故事并未在此结束
But that's not the end of the story.
我们要与混合云一起跨入下一章
With hybrid clouds, we get to write ourselves back into the next chapter.
创建混合云应用的关键可能还没有被破解
The key to creating a hybrid cloud app probably hasn't been cracked yet.
跨多云管理任务
Managing work across multiple clouds,
对于今天的代码英雄们来说将是一项艰巨的任务
that's going to be a huge job for today's command line heroes.
需要长期的尝试 犯下无数错误 但这是值得的
There'll be a lot of trial and error but it is so worth it,
因为我们知道
because the one thing we do know
只要坚持开源 开发者们就能将世界带向他们希望的方向
is that staying open source means developers can always build the world they want to work in.
这种灵活性
That kind of flexibility
正是紧紧抓住标志性的开源叛逆精神的诀窍
is how we're going to hold on to the rebel spirit that open source does best.
下一集是我们本季的最后一集
Next episode - our season finale -
我们将从宏观角度出发 观察开源作为一种全球现象的面貌
we are zooming out for a big picture view of what open source looks like as a global phenomenon,
其印象之深远会让你震惊
in ways that are going to surprise you.
我们也将展望开源的未来
We'll also look to the future of open source,
开发人员如何保持像林纳斯·托瓦兹这样的英雄的精神
how our developers preserving the spirit of heroes like Linus Torvalds,
就算与此同时 他们也在让自己的行业天翻地覆
even as they reinvent their industry.
《代码英雄》是一档红帽公司推出的原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
想了解更多关于本期和往期节目的信息
For more information about this and past episodes
请访问 RedHat.com/CommandLineHeroes
go to RedHat.com/CommandLineHeroes.
在那里你也可以注册我们的新闻通讯
Once you're there you can also sign up for our newsletter.
想免费获得新一期节目推送 请务必订阅本系列
To get new episodes delivered automatically for free, make sure to subscribe to the show.
只要在苹果播客、Spotify、
Just search for Command Line Heroes in Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
Google Play、CastBox
Google Play, CastBox,
和其他播客平台中搜索《代码英雄》
and other podcast players.
然后点击订阅
Then hit subscribe
你就可以第一时间收听新一期
so you'll be the first to know when new episodes are available.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek.
感谢你的聆听 编程不止
Thanks for listening and keep on coding.